Keisuke Umezawa

Email: keisuke.umezawa[at]gmail.com

Twitter: @kumezawa_ Blog(ja): Hatena Blog Blog(en): Medium

GitHub: github.com/keisuke-umezawa

Machine Learning Engineer / Engineering Manager

Profile Summary

Software and machine learning engineer with the experiences in financial modeling, search engine development, recommendation engine and content moderation system development. In most cases, I led teams to accomplish the targets by sharing objectives, requirements and schedules. When assigning tasks to someone, I think that the most important thing is delegating ownership and responsibility to motivate them.

Work Experience

2019.12-(Current) Engineering Manager: Mercari, Inc, Japan

- CRE (Customer Reriability Engineering)
 - Content moderation with item and user behavior information
 - Automatic response to customer inquiries by ML
- CRM (Customer Relationship Management)
 - Platform for predicting customer attributes
- CXI (Customer Experience Improvement)
 - Visualizing and improving retention rates for each customer experience

2018.3-2019.11 Engineer, Chief Engineering Manager: AlpacaJapan, Japan

- Leading model development for AlpacaForecast (Forex market prediction) using deep learning with data scientists
- Developed trading backtesting engine "AlpacaDB/backlight" to standardize evaluation method
- Standardize development process and team management: introduced ticketing system, scrum meeting, 1on1 and guidelines for development and communication

2017.3-(Current) Chainer Evangelist, Optuna Developer: Preferred Networks, Japan

- Responsible for increasing people who uses "Chainer"
 - Organizing chug (Chainer User Group)
 - Holding talks about the deep learning and its framework "Chainer"
 - Improving the documentation and tutorials
 - Holded more than 10 hands-ons and meetups

2016.8-2018.3 Engineer: Yahoo Japan Corporation, Japan

Developed inhouse search engines for the ad and media services

- developing inhouse search engine for advertisement distribution system with C++, Java and Python
- Instructed agile software development such as Scrum
- Instructed C++ cording in the team
- Led and productized inhouse recommendation engine for the media services
 - Leaded a data scientist and system engineers to build new deep learning based recommendation system
 - Responsible for satisfying requirements, architecture design and team management

2014.4-2016.8 Quantitative Analyst and Model Developer: the Bank of Tokyo Mitsubishi UFJ, Japan

Developed derivatives pricing model and risk management system with C++

Education

2012-2014 MSc, Department of Mechano-Informatics; Graduate School of Information Science and Technology, the University of Tokyo, Japan

human motion recognition and robot motion generation by HMM

2012.5-2012.8 Internship, at Learning Algorithms and Systems Laboratory (LASA); the

Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne (EPFL), Switzerland

2008-2012 BSc, Department of Mechano-Informatics; Faculty of Engineering, the Univer-

sity of Tokyo, Japan

Technical Experience

Product Management

Managed teams using following ideas:

- · Delegating ownership and responsibility
- 1on1
- Agile Methodology (Scrum/Kanban)
- · Ticketing tools s.t. Jira, Github projects

Programming Languages

first-lang: experienced items as follows with C++ and python

- · Object-Oriented Programming
- Design of API
- Multi-thread programming
- C++ meta programming
- · Functional programming

Basic knowledge of C++, Python, Java, sh/bash. And a fun of Rust.

System Arch-

Basic experience of RDS, KVS, Message Queue, Search Engine, Restful API

tecture Development

Basic experience of GitHub, Docker, k8s, ci/cd

Tools

Machine Learning Algorithms

Machine Learn- Implementation Experience

- linear regression, logistic regression, k-NN, k-means, Hidden Markov Model
- Deep Learning Application
 - CNN, RNN, word2vec, seq2seq, DCGAN, WaveNet, etc

Use Experience

• SVM, Ensembler, Logistic Regression, etc

Publication

• A. L. P. Ureche, K. Umezawa, Y. Nakamura and A. Billard, "Task Parameterization Using Continuous Constraints Extracted From Human Demonstrations," in IEEE Transactions on Robotics, vol. 31, no. 6, pp. 1458-1471, Dec. 2015. **link**

Extra Section

- · Certificates
 - IPA Database Specialist
- Human Languages:
 - Japanese (native speaker)
 - English (business level)